Now when we're doing comparatives These are called comparatives comparing things.
现在当我们进行比较时，这些被称为比较事物的比较。
We can also use as and when we use as we don't use then we also don't use E R and we also don't use
我们也可以使用 as 和当我们使用 as 我们不使用 then 我们也不使用 E R 我们也不使用
more or less.
或多或少。
So if you're using this or this you can say the same things often but again you're not using more you're
因此，如果你使用这个或这个，你可以经常说同样的话，但同样你没有使用更多，你是
not using less.
不要少用。
You're not using her and you're not using fan.
您没有使用她，也没有使用风扇。
This one means that two things are the same.
这意味着两件事是相同的。
OK.
好的。
So this is basically the best way to say that two things are the same same size the same quality whatever
所以这基本上是说两件东西尺寸相同，质量相同的最好方式
you want to say.
你想说。
And the cool thing about it is it doesn't matter how many syllables there are there are two syllables
最酷的一点是，有多少个音节并不重要，有两个音节
or three syllables.
或三个音节。
If there's one syllable one hundred syllables No no one hundred syllable words doesn't matter.
如果有一个音节一百个音节没有没有一百个音节的话没有关系。
Ok not as same.
好吧，不一样。
It doesn't matter.
没关系。
The difficulty here is that this as as means they're equal but this means that one is less than another.
这里的困难在于，这意味着它们是平等的，但这意味着一个小于另一个。
So they're not exactly opposites.
所以它们并不完全相反。
OK just means one is actually less it's the same as saying less then.
好的只是意味着一个实际上更少它与说更少是一样的。
OK.
好的。
So let's look at some examples.
所以让我们看一些例子。
Sharman is as warm as Hong Kong warm.
沙曼和香港一样温暖。
We can put in other words here we could say humid humid.
换句话说，我们可以在这里说潮湿潮湿。
OK.
好的。
We could say longer words we could say Charlotte is as interesting as Hong Kong.
我们可以说更长的词，我们可以说夏洛特和香港一样有趣。
Doesn't matter how many syllables we have.
不管我们有多少音节。
And it means again in my mind they're the same.
在我看来，这再次意味着它们是相同的。
Of course it's my opinion it's my opinion I am or I'm as smart as my brother.
当然，这是我的看法，我的看法是我或我和我兄弟一样聪明。
We could say other words here longer words as intellectual as my brother as maybe interesting or whatever
我们可以在这里说更长的词，像我兄弟一样聪明，也许有趣或其他
we want to say it doesn't matter.
我们想说没关系。
It means we're equal.
这意味着我们是平等的。
OK.
好的。
But when we use not as something as it means the first thing we say is less then the second thing we
但是当我们使用 not as something 时，它意味着我们说的第一件事比我们说的第二件事要少
say.
说。
So it's sort of like saying my house is less expensive than his house My house is not as expensive as
所以这有点像说我的房子比他的房子便宜我的房子没有他的房子贵
his house.
他的房子。
So those two are the same.
所以这两个是一样的。
It's almost the same.
这几乎是一样的。
It is the same as using less then less expensive then not as expensive as it's the same.
这与使用更少然后更便宜然后不那么昂贵是一样的。
Same meaning.
同样的意思。
So let's look at some examples.
所以让我们看一些例子。
This coffee is not quite as good as Starbucks.
这种咖啡不如星巴克好。
Now why would we sometimes say not as good as instead of using less well Remember less is only used
现在为什么我们有时会说不如使用 less 而不是 well 记住 less 仅用于
when we have two or three or more syllables.
当我们有两个或三个或更多音节时。
So if we want to use words like good it's often very useful to use as instead because we can't say less
因此，如果我们想使用 good 这样的词，通常使用 as 非常有用，因为我们不能少说
good than we would have to change the whole sentence and we would say we would have to say this coffee
好过我们不得不改变整个句子，我们会说我们不得不说这杯咖啡
is worse than Starbucks but maybe that doesn't give us the right feeling because worse makes this coffee
比星巴克差，但也许这并没有给我们正确的感觉，因为更糟糕的是制作这种咖啡
look really really bad.
看起来真的很糟糕。
Maybe people will judge it too much but what we really want to say is Starbucks is here and this coffee
也许人们会过分评判，但我们真正想说的是星巴克来了，这杯咖啡
is a little bit less just here.
只是这里少了一点。
And so we can use not as good as because it doesn't mean much less.
所以我们可以使用不如，因为它并不意味着更少。
It can just be a little bit.
它可能只是一点点。
This coffee is not quite as good as Starbucks by adding quite here.
在这里添加的咖啡不如星巴克好。
I focus on the fact that they're nearby.
我专注于他们在附近的事实。
They're nearby they're close.
他们就在附近。
It's almost as good as almost as good as Starbucks but not quite as good.
它几乎和星巴克一样好，但没有那么好。
So again this is a very useful way to be able to express not that something is negative or completely
因此，这又是一种非常有用的方式，可以不表达某事是消极的或完全的是的
opposite but that it's just less and we can use the same adjective.
相反，但它只是更少，我们可以使用相同的形容词。
Doesn't matter how many syllables so it's a great way to do it.
不管有多少音节，这是一个很好的方法。
And we can add words like quite to say that it's very close and nearly to say that it's very far.
我们可以添加类似相当的词来表示它非常接近并且几乎表示它非常远。
So this is like this coffee and there's Starbucks.
所以这就像这杯咖啡，还有星巴克。
This one I'm not nearly as old as him.
这个我没有他那么大。
This means the distance is very far.
这意味着距离很远。
It's like saying I'm much younger than him I am much younger younger than him.
这就像说我比他年轻得多，我比他年轻得多。
So this one is like maybe he's I don't know 50 and I'm 24 much younger not as old as same K same.
所以这个就像也许他是我不知道 50 和我 24 比同一个 K 一样年轻得多。
So we don't have to change the adjective.
所以我们不必改变形容词。
And from our example that we'll look at in a minute you'll see how this is a really useful way to express
从我们稍后将看到的示例中，您会看到这是一种非常有用的表达方式
that something is less.
那东西少了。